{
  "title": "PBL of Endocrine", 
  "questions": [
    {
      "stem": "Most common cause of congenital hypothyroidism:",
      "options": [
        "Maternal antithyroid drugs",
        "Dyshormonogenesis",
        "Aplasia"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "stem": "All of the following are precipitating factors of DKA except:",
      "options": [
        "Infection",
        "Psychological stress",
        "Physical trauma",
        "Over dose of insulin"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "Type I diabetes mellitus is an:",
      "options": [
        "infectious disease",
        "Autoimmune disease",
        "vascular disease",
        "congenital disease"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "Clinical triad of Coma, dehydration and audotie breathing in not known diabetic child should raise the possibilty of DKA.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "stem": "Correction of shock, acidosis & dehydration by IV fluid is the most urgent line of therapy in DKA.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "stem": "Which of the following is true about DKA?",
      "options": [
        "Triad of dehydration, Acidosis & Coma",
        "fatal in 10% of diabetic children",
        "May be 1st manifestation in 20% of diabetes",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "Diabetes mellitus presents by all of the following except:",
      "options": [
        "Polyuria, polydipsia",
        "Primary nocturnal enuresis",
        "DKA represents the initial presentation in 10-20% of cases.",
        "Recent weight loss"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "All of the following are acute complications of TYPE I Diabetes mellitus except:",
      "options": [
        "Infections",
        "Hypoglycemia",
        "DKA",
        "Ischemic heart disease"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "All of the following statements about DKA management are true except:",
      "options": [
        "Initial plasma potassium may be low or high",
        "The use of bicarbonate for correction of acidosis in DKA is not recommended early",
        "Insulin therapy started after 1h from fluid therapy",
        "0.9 % saline is used in hyperosmolar cases"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "Which of the following is an acute complication for type 1 DM in children?",
      "options": [
        "Microvasculopathy",
        "Diabetic ketoacidosis",
        "Delayed puberty",
        "Ischemic heart disease",
        "Diabetic foot"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "Insulin deficiency is associated with:",
      "options": [
        "Reduced lipolysis",
        "Increased ketogenesis",
        "Reduced gluconeogenesis",
        "Reduced proteolysis",
        "Glycogenesis"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "All of the following investigations for congenital hypothyroidism are true except:",
      "options": [
        "Low T4",
        "High TSH",
        "Delayed bone age",
        "Thyroid scanning is essential for diagnosis of the cause.",
        "High T3"
      ],
      "correct": 4
    },
    {
      "stem": "Congenital Hypothyroidism associated with all of the following except?",
      "options": [
        "widely opened anterior fontanels",
        "Goiter may be present",
        "Lifelong therapy with L thyroxin",
        "Short stature",
        "Normal motor and mental development"
      ],
      "correct": 4
    },
    {
      "stem": "All of the following are true about the management of DKA EXCEPT:",
      "options": [
        "IV fluid Correction must be gradual as rapid rehydration lead to cerebral edema.",
        "When blood glucose has fallen to≤ 300 mg/dl add glucose to the IV fluids to avoid hypoglycemia.",
        "If the patient shows mild dehydration, you start the deficit + maintenance therapy without bolus fluids.",
        "Insulin therapy starts with resuscitation fluid therapy.",
        "Diabetic ketoacidosis represents the initial presentation of DM in 10-20 % of cases."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "Which statement isn`t true regarding Potassium therapy during of management of DKA?",
      "options": [
        "Initial plasma potassium level may be low or high.",
        "Potassium therapy start after the IV fluid resuscitation",
        "Potassium therapy start after the patient passes urine provided K is not elevated.",
        "Plasma potassium level will rise following treatment with insulin.",
        "Potassium is added 30-40 mEq/L after the first hour of IV fluid therapy."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "stem": "A one year old child presented with the history of short stature, tiredness and constipation. Examination revealed a palpable goiter, Serum T4 was decreased and TSH levels were increased. Which is the most probable diagnosis?",
      "options": [
        "Thyroid agenesis",
        "Thyroid Dyshormonogenesis",
        "Ectopia thyroid",
        "Central hypothyroidism"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "Iodine deficiency can cause:",
      "options": [
        "Goitre",
        "Thyroid cancer",
        "Solitary thyroid nodules",
        "Thyroiditis"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "stem": "In type 1 diabetes, the pancreas can’t make insulin because:",
      "options": [
        "The child is overweight or obese",
        "The body’s immune system has attacked the pancreas",
        "The patient eats more simple carbs than the body can handle",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "children with type 1 diabetes need to:",
      "options": [
        "Lose weight",
        "Take insulin in shots or with a pump",
        "Remove sugar from their diets",
        "Take oral hypoglycemic pills"
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "stem": "What is the first step in the management of diabetic ketoacidosis?",
      "options": [
        "To provide fluids intravenously",
        "To provide insulin",
        "To provide bicarbonate",
        "To initiate insulin and fluids simultaneously"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    }
  ]
}
